Virginia Radley Papers
State University of New York at Oswego
- Speeches, June, 1980 - December, 1980 (Box-folder 1-21)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following: Elizabeth Barrett Browning. Conversations in the Discipline. Brockport, New York. June 13, 1980. Seven typed pages. 3 copies, two with editing notes. St. Lawrence Conference. June 22-24, 1980. Eight typed pages, edited. Draft. General Faculty Meeting. September 4, 1980. Three typed pages, edited. Outline of Remarks to Faculty Chairpeople. September 11, 1980. Seven typed pages, edited. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, January, 1981 - May, 1981 (Box-folder 1-22)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley includes information about the State University and SUNY Oswego and the following: Faculty Assembly speech. February 5, 1981. Includes a 12-page version, edited, and a 7-page version and a 4-page draft. Typed. Faculty Meeting. March 18, 1981. Includes and 6 and 7 page versions. Typed. Annual Conference of the American Industrial Arts Association speech, "Excellence in Teaching". March 24, 1981. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, June, 1981 - December, 1981 (Box-folder 1-23)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following: Retirement dinner for faculty and staff on Thursday evening, June 11, 1981. 2 typed pages. Bryn Mawr Summer Institute. July 27, 1981. 14 typed pages. Also includes 15-page typed draft, edited. Sheldon Associates. August 22, 1981. Two typed pages, edited. New Students. August 31, 1981. Two page draft, edited. General Faculty speech. September 3, 1981. Ten typed and handwritten pages, edited. New Professors. September 10, 1981. One typed page. "How To Shrink Effectively, Humanely". October 14, 1981. Five typed pages, edited. "Welcome to all... at your Alma Mater". n.d. 3 typed pages. Photocopy with lyrics and music, "Gaudeamus Igitur". "Circe and the Colossus: Seductive Factors on the Horizon". (March 1979, Calif.) 9-page typed speech. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, January, 1982 - April, 1982 (Box-folder 1-24)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley includes the following: "What Steps are Being Taken to Facilitate Full Realization of Female Potential?" 5 typed pages, edited. n.d. 6 handwritten pages, "re: deployment, retraining, reallocation". n.d. Approaches to Leadership: The Team Concept. 10 typed pages. n.d. The Sounding Furrows Smote Again: Leadership and Common Sense. 13 typed pages. Second draft. Includes bibliography. n.d. How to Shrink Effectively, Humanely. 4 typed pages. n.d. Faculty Meeting. February 4, 1982. Nine typed pages, edited. 2 copies. Languages at Oswego. February 1982. Two typed pages with editing notes. Faculty Speech. Draft. 3 typed pages, edited. n.d. Salvation Army Dinner. March 25, 1982. Draft. 3 typed pages. Includes event program. Guest Editorial for Palladium-Times. March 23, 1982. 2 typed pages. "Sauntering Among the 'Bloomsberries' " February 10, 1982. Friends of Penfield Library speech. 3 typed pages with editorial notes. Includes 4 photocopied pages from 1921 publication excerpt, "To Lytton Strachey". 9 pages of handwritten notes for address given at American Studies Association, R. Freeman Butts Lecture. November 5, 1981. 7 pages of handwritten notes of the State of SUNY. March 1982. Research and Truth. Remarks by Dr. V. L. Radley, at Quest 1982. April 7, 1982. Four typed pages. College Open House. April 19, 1982. Eight pages of handwritten notes. Freedom and Responsiblity. April 28, 1982. Guest editorial, Palladium-Times. 3 typed pages. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, May, 1982 - December, 1982 (Box-folder 1-25)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following: Managing for Growth with Diminishing Resources Or How To Do More With Less. Draft. Skytop speech. November 18, 1982. Nine typed pages, edited. 3 copies. October 16, 1982, speech to 1,100 parents. 10 typed and handwritten pages, edited. Faculty Speech. September 2, 1982. Six typed pages. Enhancing Public Perception of Quality of SUNY's Programs. September 1982. Draft. 4 typed and handwritten pages, edited. American Council on Education Fellows Program in Florida. September 1982. Eleven typed pages, edited. Sheldon Association Luncheon. August 7, 1982. Three handwritten pages. Say Not the Struggle Nought Availeth. July 18, 1982. Bryn Mawr. 12 typed pages, edited. Cultivating External Constituencies. Draft. July 18, 1982. Bryn Mawr. 10 typed pages, edited. The Best of All Possible Worlds. Wells College Honors Convocation. May 11, 1982. 10 typed pages, edited. Includes Wells College press release pertaining to the Dr. Radley and the Honors Convocation. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, 1983 (Box-folder 1-26)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley include the following: Press release quoting Dr. Radley about SUNY Oswego fiscal issues. December 1983. 8 pages of handwritten and typed notes for "Dr. Spencer's class". November 11, 1983. Remarks for AAUW. November 1983. Eight typed pages titled, Networks. Meeting of Admissions staff. October 19, 1983. Seven handwritten pages. Also includes State University of New York College Admissions Personnel bifold, "Operation Inform '83". Sheldon Associates. August 1983. Three pages of handwritten notes. 5-page typed draft titled, "Mentoring". July 1983. Includes editorial notes. Faculty Senates speech. April 15, 1983. Two typed pages with editorial notes. 3-page typed speech with editorial notes. Title - "Open House". April 11, 1983. Talk to Student Association Senate. March 2, 1983. 4-page draft with editorial notes. Draft of Faculty Meeting speech. February 10, 1983. 10 typed pages. "Guides, Philos. + Friends" - Mentors. 8 handwritten pages with editorial notes. n.d. Conversations in the Disciplines. April 1983. One typed page. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, 1984 (Box-folder 1-27)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley include the following: 6 pages of handwritten notes for an unspecified speech. n.d. Speech to Faculty. August 27, 1984. 3-page typed draft with editorial notes. Speech to Food Service Personnel. August 20, 1984. 3-page typed draft with editorial notes. Alumni Weekend speech. July 15, 1984. 4-page handwritten notes. Language Fair. May 5, 1984. 4-page typed speech. Speech to Faculty. April 1984. 6 pages, typed and handwritten. Includes the following topics - Observations for Fall 1984, Preliminary Assessment Indicates, faculty recognition, budget, the Oswegonian, and admissions. Notes for Presidential Forum. March 1984. Eight handwritten pages. Faculty Meeting remarks. February 8, 1984. Six handwritten pages. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, 1985 (Box-folder 1-28)
  Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following: General Faculty Meeting. February 6, 1985. Seven handwritten pages. Attached is an article from Science, Vol. 227, January 1985, by Constance Holden, "Restoration of the Humanities Urged. NEH chairman decries 'garage sale' look of college curricula; says it's time to get back to the classics". "The Interior World of the Intellect: Jubilee Celebration at Marymount Manhattan College in New York City". November 24, 1985. Seven typed pages with editing notations signed Dr. Virginia L. Radley. "Professors Convocation Recognition". October 1985. Two typed pages with editing notes. Unsigned. Chamber of Commerce Breakfast. October 7, 1985. Three handwritten pages. Unsigned. 5-page handwritten speech to the faculty. September 1985. "Topics for Speech to the Men's Honor Society". September 19, 1985. Seven typed pages. 2 copies. Attached are two letters from Oswego graduates Joanne Cono and Melissa Bettinger. Also included is a copy of a handwritten letter to Governor Cuomo from an Elderhostel participant, Ceil Gordet. Alumni Welcome. July 13, 1985. Thirteen pages of handwritten notes (red ink). Sheldon Association. July 1985. Five pages of handwritten notes (red ink). Faculty Retirement Dinner. May 30, 1985. Nine handwritten pages. Networking. April 19, 1985. 3 pages of handwritten notes. Includes pamphlet for New York Women's Studies Association Eighth Annual Conference (at SUNY Oswego), "The New Feminist Scholarship. Images & Visions". Also includes "Bridging the Gap: Networking for Women" announcement, agenda and registration form. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Speeches, n.d. (Box-folder 1-29)
  Undated speeches of Dr. Viginia L. Radley including the following: Fidessa-Duessa: Perceptions of a Woman Administrator in a Male Dominated Institution. Speech delivered by Dr. Virginia L. Radley, Executive Vice President/Provost, State University College of Arts and Sciences, Oswego, New York. 15 typed pages. 2 copies. 7 pages of handwritten notes. n.d. "The next 100 years - " 6 pages of handwritten notes. n.d. "What every woman Ph.D. should know if she aspires to be an administrator". Middle States Chairs. n.d. 8 handwritten pages. "Women in management". n.d. 4 pages of handwritten notes. Wingspread Conference Speech. "The 1980's: Women and Higher Education". 7 typed pages with editing notes. Onionskin. Presidential statement. The issue of quality. 7 typed pages with editing notes. n.d. "Upward Mobility for Women". 5 typed pages. n.d. Onionskin. "Women and the Arts". 4 typed pages with editing notes. n.d. Also includes notes for untitled and undated speeches. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Published works, 1963 - 1974 (Box-folder 1-30)
  Published works of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following: "Discipline Versus the 'Viewless Wings of Poesy' " by Virginia L. Radley. Reprint from Liberal Education, Vol. XLIX, No. 4, December 1963. Pages 1-6. Three reprints. Two photocopies. "The Humanist Dean and Management Systems". Reprint from Liberal Education, May 1974, Vol. LX, No. 2. Pages 228 - 235. 4 copies (variations and 1 photocopy) "Involvement of Women in the Governance Process: Decision Making". 2 typed copies. 16 pages. Published by the New York State Education Department. Spring 1974. "Christabel: Directions Old and New". Studies in English Literature. Volume IV, Number 4, Autumn 1964. Pages 531 - 541. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Inauguration, 1978 (Box-folder 1-31)
  Papers relating to Dr. Virginia L. Radley's inauguration as the eighth President of SUNY Oswego. Included are the following: Correspondence and memorandums, meeting minutes, in regards to the planning and administrative duties for Dr. Radley's inauguration. Correspondents include David Nellis, Dr. Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., Public Ceremonies Committee, Provost Ralph Spencer, Dr. Dorothy Rogers, Patti M. Peterson, Margaret Richardson, Rosemary Nesbitt, David Glick, Lynn Hemink, Michael D. Jones, Steven D. Sucher, Dr. J. Michael Adams, Dr. John Knapp, Henry Angle, Donald Batchelor, Margaret Richardson, Dr. Judy Wellman, and Martin Lindenmayer. Flyer for the President's Colloquia, October 5 - 7, 1978. Two copies. Colloquium introduction. 3 typed pages. Inauguration agenda. 5 pages. "Oswego Alumni Association Presents Homecoming Dinner and Presidential Ball, October 7, 1978". Program. Bifold with insert of agenda. "Alumni and Parents Homecoming Weekend featuring The Installation of Virginia L. Radley Oswego's Eighth President. October 6 - 8, 1978. Trifold program with photographs. "The Inauguration of Dr. Virginia L. Radley as the eighth President of The State University of New York College of Arts and Sciences at Oswego". Bifold program with Schedule of Events insert. 3 copies. "The Infinite Kingdom of Mind". Inaugural address of Dr. Virginia L. Radley. President's Colloquia schedule of events with correspondence from participants - Joseph Weicha, Ronald Brown and Diana Balmori. "The Language of the Discipline". (Formerly 1/9/92)
- Dr. Virginina L. Radley- Resignation, 1987 (Box-folder 1-32)
  Letters, memorandum, publications, remarks and newspaper clippings concerning Dr. Virginia L. Radley's resignation. Correspondents include the following: Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., Chancellor, State University of New York. Dr. Jerome B. Kosimer, Executive Vice Chancellor, State University of New York. John T. Sullivan, Jr. Office of Public Affairs news release. September 3, 1987. Faculty Meeting remarks by Dr. Radley. September 3, 1987. John Kares Smith, Professor of Communications Studies, SUNY Oswego. Helena Howe, Cayuga County Community College President Emeritus. Muriel Allerton "City Will Be Poorer When Radley Exits". Palladium-Times, September 8, 1987. Sanford Sternlicht Dorothy P. Heindel Elizabeth Ward, Director, Russsell Sage College Alumnae Association. Coy (Ludwig?) Humphrey Tonkin, President, Potsdam College. Howard L. Simmons, Ph.D., Associate Director, Middle States Association. Jeffrey W. Hurrin (Class of '79), SUNY New Paltz. Prentiss Carnell III, President, Albany Business College. Frank Horton, U.S.Congressman, New York. F. H. Ratzeburg, SUNY Oswego professor, Psychology Department. Sylvia Chu, SUNY Oswego. Andrew D. Hopkins, University of Rochester. Dr. Sherron Knopp, Williams College. Susan Donnelly, Registrar, Bunker Hill Community College, Boston, MA. Judith Davidson Moyers, Board of Trustees, State University of New York. Also included is Dr. Virginia L. Radley's vitae. Bifold. 4 copies. (Formerly 1/9/217)
- Dr. Virginia L. Radley- Biography, 1978 (Box-folder 1-33)
  2-page typed biography of Dr. Radley. Not cited. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Other correspondence, 1978 - 1994 (Box-folder 1-34)
  Correspondence from the office of Dr. Virginia L. Radley. Correspondents include: Dolores B. Schmidt, Assistant Vice Chancellor for Affirmative Action, SUNY. Dr. Foster S. Brown John J. Castle (Class of 1934) Grace McCarthy Knitter writes about her memories of Oswego as a child (1906 - 1916). Harriette Laudise writes concerning a donation of copies of newspaper clippings about Emily Howland. Phebe M. King writes concerning publications and papers by and about Emily Howland. Margaret Karch Lasky David Nellis Talk by Dr. Dorothy Rogers. Founders Day. Professor Recognition Ceremony. September 10, 1981. Four typed pages. Paper by Dr. Dorothy Rogers. "The All-Time Greats". 6 typed pages. n.d. Includes information about Hermann Krusi, Richard K. Piez, Ralph W. Swetman, Caroline L. G. Scales, Isaac B. Poucher, Matilda Cooper Poucher, Amos Farnham, Margaret K. Smith, Henry Straight, Emma Dickinson Straight, Caroline V. Sinnamon, Clara Armstrong, Hideo Takamine, Ellor Carlile Ripley, Mary Sheldon Barnes, and Earl Barnes. Judy Wellman Anne C. Edmonds, College Librarian, Mount Holyoke College. Memories/biography of Dr. Radley. July 1983. (Formerly 1/9/92)
- Dr. Virginia Radley- Photographs, 1980's (Box-folder 1-35)
  12 black and white photographs. Digital versions of these photos can be found in the Image Management area of this record. Photograph descriptions as follows: Dr. Radley in academic robes. (Part of 2006.024 Accession.) 5" x 7" -2 Dr. Radley and 3 unidentified male students at Shady Shore. 5" x 7" -3 Dr. Virginia L. Radley, far right. 5" x 7" - 4 Dr. Radley. Head and shoulders, partial profile. 3" x 2". Two photographs. - 5 Dr. Radley, left, at Shady Shore greeting an unidentified woman. c. 1980's. 5" x 7" - 6 Foster S. Brown, left, and Dr. Virginia L. Radley in front of Shady Shore. c. 1980's. 8" x 10" - 7 Dr. Virginia L. Radley at her desk in Culkin Hall. c. 1980's. 5" x 7" - 8 Dr. Virginia L. Radley. c. 1980's. 5" x 7" - 9 Dr. Virginia L. Radley, left, in academic robe and mortat board. 5" x 7" - 10 Dr. Radley at her desk. 1985. From the Undergraduate Catalog, page 3. ( 5" x 7". 2 copies. Third copy is 8" x 4" - 11 Dr. Virginia L. Radley, right, at podium. Torchlight Ceremony. 1987. Sheldon Statue is in the background. 8" x 10" - 12 Dr. Radley at podium. c. 1970's. 8" x 10" (Photos 2 through 12 were formerly with archive # 52/1/192)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1974 - 1979 (Box-folder 2-1)
  Clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley, including the following: "Highest Ranking Woman in SUNY". The Oswegonian, August 1, 1974. "Addresses AAUW. Broader Issues of Higher Education Dr. Radley Topic". The Palldium-Times. December 2, 1974. "Radley defies college stereotype" by Dick Schulman. The Oswegonian. December 21, 1976. "Radley's Name Not Included On Faculty List". Palladium-Times. March 6, 1978. Letters to the Editor in response to March 6th article. Palladium-TImes. March 19, 1978. Press release from the Office of Public Relations concerning the appointment of Dr. Radley as president of SUNY Oswego. March 22, 1978. "Dr. Radley New SUNY Oswego President". Palladium-Times. March 22, 1978. "Oswego president. Woman joins SUNY elite". Syracuse Herald-Journal. March 23, 1978. "Dr. Virginia Radley Named SUNY Oswego President" by Luther F. Bliven. Syracuse Post-Standard. March 23, 1978. "Radley chosen as eighth SUCO president" by Scott Stafford. Oswegonian. March 24, 1978. "Dr. Radley Receives Permanent Nod from Trustees". Perspective. March 29, 1978. "Oswego college president a former Nazareth dean". Rochester Democrat and Chronicle. March 30, 1978. "Krupsak seeks student action". Syracuse Herald-Journal. March 30, 1978. "Oswego college president a former Nazareth dean" by Kevin Dilworth. Rochester Democrat and Chronicle. March 30, 1978. "Krupsak Sees 'Overreaction' Possible in Lake Ban". Palladium-Times. March 30, 1978. "Dr. Radley Moving to Form Adminstrative Team". Palladium-Times. April 24, 1978. "Adminstrative Team Members Sought by SUCO President". Palladium-Times. May 22, 1978. "Radley Named to Bank Council". Palladium-Times. May 25, 1978. Photograph of Dr. Foster S. Brown and Dr. Virginia L. Radley in front of Shady Shore. Syracuse Herald-Journal. October 1978. "The Boss at Oswego" by Richard G. Case. Empire magazine, The Syracuse Herald-American. August 27, 1978. "Iron Fist in a Velvet Glove. SUNY Oswego's new president, Virginia Radley, has definite ideas about how a college should be run". Syracuse Alumni Quarterly, Fall 1978. 3 copies "Inauguration of Radley to highlight Alumni weekend". Oswegonian, September 28, 1978. "Medal of Office Designed For Radley Innauguration". Palladium-Times, October 5, 1978. "President's Colloquia Features Inaugural Program". Palladium-Times, October 6, 1978. "Dr. Radley Inaugurated as President at SUNY Oswego". Includes photograph. The Palladium-Times. October 7, 1978. "College president inauguration. Radley takes reins". Syracuse Herald-American. October 8, 1978. "Dr. Radley Assumes Presidency at SUCO". Palladium-Times, October 9, 1978. Includes 4 photographs with captions. "Virginia Radley: Ready When the Opportunity Came". November 15, 1978. "Women Have Played Role in Development of SUCO". Palladium-Times, December 4, 1978. "Woman Heads SUNY College". Palladium-Times. January 31, 1979. "Dr. Radley Honored By Legislature". March 12, 1979. "Legislature commends President Radley". April 1979. The SUNY News. "College President Declares Hiring Moratorium. Budget Sparks Action". Palladium-Times, November 9, 1979. "Now on Sentry Board - Dr. Radley In Demand". Palladium-Times, November 29, 1979 (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1980 - 1981 (Box-folder 2-2)
  Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley. "Demonstrating Role Model". February 18, 1980. Syracuse Post-Standard. "Radley Muzzling Council?" Palladium-Times, February 21, 1980. "Research Pact Signed Here". Photograph and caption, "Officials at SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry and SUNY Oswego sign cooperative programming pact to increase inter-campus cooperation in research, public service and educational programs in the natural and environmental sciences. Seated (from left) are Dr. Ralph Spencer, Oswego provost; Dr. Edward Palmer, ESF president; Dr. Virginia Radley, Oswego president; and Dr. Donald Behrend, ESF vice president for program affairs. Standing (from left) are ESF and Oswego officials including Dr. Ronald Scrudato, Dr. James Geis, Dr. Robert Gubbi Sachidanandan, Dr. Kathryn Martin, and Dr. John Gannon". Palladium-Times, April 25, 1980. "Overview of women in higher education" by Dorothy Austin. Milwaukee Sentinel. April 29, 1980. "Women in Higher Education: Past, Present, Future. Highlights of Wingspread Conference, April 28 - 29, 1980". Comment. June, 1980. "So You Want to Be a College President" by Lee Hall. The Chronicle. July 21, 1980. Page 48. "SUCO Union Attacks Radley". Oswego Valley News, December 23, 1980. "Low Morale at SUCO". Oswego Valley News, March 10, 1981. "Women Presidents Make the Grade at Area Colleges". Includes article on Dr. Radley and Patti McGill Peterson. The Post-Standard. November 3, 1981. "SUCO President Explains Firing Procedure". The Post-Standard. November 24, 1981.
- Newspaper Clippings, 1982 (Box-folder 2-3)
  Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley. "Women's World 1982. 19th Century Scholar Is 20th Century Woman". Palladium-Times. January 11, 1982. "Contract Signing -- Peg Hamilton (front row far right) watches as Dr. Virginia Radley puts her signature on a one-year pact that will allow the Senior Citizens Nutrition Program to move to the Swetman Hall cafetorium effective Monday. Also on hand for the signing Wednesday morning were Oswego County Opportunities Executive Director Peter Geiter (front row, far left) and college administrators Dr. Willard Schum (top right) and Bernie Henderson (top left)... " Palladium-Times, February 27, 1982. "Despite rumors, Radley's staying". Oswegonian News. March 11, 1982. "SUCO President to Give Talk at Salvation Army". Oswego County Messenger, March 11, 1982. "SUCO President To Address Reps On Budget Impact". Oswego County Messenger, March 12, 1982. "Dr. Radley In Washington: Aid Cuts Foreshadow Problems". Palladium-Times, March 16, 1982. "D'Amato Calms Fears Of College Presidents". March 18, 1982. "SUCO President Deplores 'Pot Shots' ". Oswego County Messenger, March 29, 1982. "There is danger in ignorance concerning 'Gulliver' ". Dr. Donald Vanouse. Oswegonian. April 22, 1982. "Freedom, Responsibility Go Hand in Hand" by Dr. Virginia Radley. Palladium-Times. May 12, 1982. "Radley forum" by Andy Leahy. Oswegonian News. May 13, 1982. "Two Oswego County Women To be Honored". Oswego County Messenger, September 9, 1982. "Radley Speaks Out On Education". Palladium-Times, September 15, 1982. "Educator Honored - Dr. Virginia Radley... is presented with the 'Trailblazer in Education' award by Dr. Helena Bain Howe on behalf of the Central New York chapter, National Organization of Women". Oswego Valley News, October 28, 1982. "9 Unsung Heroines to Be Honored. The Oswego County Messenger. September 27, 1982. "Chamber of Commerce Honors Dr. Radley" by Antone Clark. Palladium-Times. December 1, 1982. "Women's rating guide gives Syracuse University just 1 star" by Hart Seely. Herald-Journal Metro. December 1, 1982. "Chamber of Commerce Honors Dr. Radley". Palladium-Times, December 1, 1982. "Radley looks ahead to college's future plans" by Patricia Culligan. Oswegonian. December 2, 1982. "Radley: SUNY in Trouble" by Antone Clark. The Palladium-Times. December 2, 1982. "Oswego State Scores Well in Women's Guide to Colleges". The Post-Standard. December 3, 1982. "An Impressive Public Figure". Palladium-Times. December 3, 1982. "Radley comments on Oswego as an institution" by Patricia Culligan. Oswegonian News. December 9, 1982.
- Newspaper Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 2-4)